Hamilton, Ontario, Canada

□ (+1) (905) 525-9140 x24807 | 🗷 ktmeaton@gmail.com | 🔏 ktmeaton.github.io | 🎓 Google Scholar

Summary

Katherine is a multidisciplinary researcher, bridging the gap between the sciences as a computational biologist, and the humanities as an anthropologist of infectious disease. As a senior PhD candidate, she is occupied with writing papers, giving conference talks, and supporting laboratory training and facility operations.

Education

McMaster University Hamilton, Canada

PhD in Anthropology

- Plague Phylogeography: Novel Synthesis and Geospatial Analysis
- · Dr. Hendrik Poinar

University of Toronto Mississauga

Mississauga, Canada

2014 - Present

2013 - 2014

OPEN STUDIES

- · Coursework in Computer Science, Mathematics, and Bioinformatics.
- · Dr. Esteban Parra

University of Alberta Edmonton, Alberta

B.A. IN ANTHROPOLOGY 2009 - 2013

- Evaluation of bodeterioration in deer bone inoculated with Amycolatopsis sp. using SEM.
- Pamela Mayne Correia

Work Experience

McMaster University Hamilton, Canada

MASTERS-TO-PHD FAST-TRACK STUDENT (DEPT. OF ANTHROPOLOGY)

2014 - Present

- Provide undergraduate-level course instruction and assessment (ANTH and BIO).
- · Provide graduate-level training in laboratory techniques and computational analysis.

McMaster University Hamilton, Canada

RESEARCH ASSISTANT (McMaster Ancient DNA Centre)

2019 - 2021

2017 - 2021

2017 - 2018

2012 - 2013

2011 - 2013

- · Bioinformatic Analysis.
- · Manuscript Preparation.
- · DNA Extraction, NGS Library Prep, Bacterial Genome Sequencing.

Lewis & Ruth Sherman Centre for Digital Scholarship

Hamilton, Canada

GRADUATE RESIDENT

• Software development for high-throughput genomic analyses.

MacData Institute Hamilton, Canada

GRADUATE FELLOW

• Formation of the new McMaster Digital Pedagogy Working Group.

· Graduate Colloquium presentation, community building.

University of Toronto Mississauga Mississauga, Canada

VOLUNTEER (DEPT. OF ANTHROPOLOGY) 2013 - 2014

• Annotation of genes associated with pigmentation in East Asian populations.

University of Alberta Edmonton, Canada

Undergraduate Thesis Student, (Dept. of Anthropology) · Scanning Electron Microscopy (SEM) of bone.

University of Alberta Edmonton, Canada

VOLUNTEER, SUMMER STUDENT (DEPT. OF SURGERY) • Molecular biology assays and cell tissue culture, DNA sequence analysis.

• Immunodetection of genes involved in skeletal development.

BYUNGJIN PARK · RÉSUMÉ JULY 19, 2021

Public Output _____

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATION

2020	A Black Death mass grave at Thornton Abbey, Lincolnshire: the discovery, Co-Author	Journal
2020	NCBImeta: efficient and comprehensive metadata retrieval from NCBI databases, Author	Journal
2019	Genetic resiliency and the Black Death: No apparent loss of mitogenomic, Co-Author	Journal

PRESENTATION

2021	Plague phylogeography: Novel synthesis and geospatial analysis, Presenter	Podium
2020	Presenting "The Plague": Digital exhibits as interdisciplinary method, Presenter	Exhibit
2019	Digging into digital anthropology: Project-based learning, Presenter	Podium

SOFTWARE

2021	Automatically create release notes and a changelog, Developer	Github
2016	Efficient and comprehensive metadata acquisition from the NCBI databases, Developer	Github

Honors & Awards

RESEARCH

2019	HASTAC Scholars Fellowship, \$600	International
2019	Sherman Centre for Digital Scholarship Bursary, \$500	Hamilton, Canada
2018	Anthropology Graduate Conference and Travel Competition, \$600	Hamilton, Canada
2012	Undergraduate Research Initiative, \$250	Edmonton, Canada
2012	Collective Body for Arts Students Individual Grant, \$500	Edmonton, Canada

ACADEMIC

2019-202	McMaster Graduate Bursary, \$3400	Hamilton, Canada
2016-2019	Joseph-Armand Bombardier CGS Doctoral Scholarship, \$105000	Hamilton, Canada
2017	MacDATA Graduate Fellowship, \$7500	Hamilton, Canada
2015	Canadian Graduate Scholarship Master's Program, \$17500	Hamilton, Canada
2014-2017	7 Anthropology Graduate Scholarship, \$16000	Hamilton, Canada
2013	University of Toronto Advanced Planning for Students Grant, \$5000	Mississauga, Canada
2012	Erindale Bursary, \$800	Mississauga, Canada
2010-2012	2 Suncore Energy Scholarship, \$3000	Edmonton, Canada
2009-202	1 Jason Lang Scholarship, \$4000	Edmonton, Canada